<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Quanshun Mei</title>
    <link>/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {2021} Qsmei</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>blupADC-C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/project/blupadc_c&#43;&#43;/blupadc_c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/blupadc_c&#43;&#43;/blupadc_c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using C++ to re-write R package-blupADC to improve the  speed and memory performance!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rlmt</title>
      <link>/project/rlmt/rlmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/rlmt/rlmt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Linear mixed Models Toolbox (lmt) is a stand-alone single executable software for for large scale linear mixed model analysis. lmt has been used successfully for genetic evaluation data sets with &amp;raquo;200k genotyped animals, &amp;raquo;15m animals, &amp;raquo;500m equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to further assistance the use of lmt, I developed an R package: Rlmt for interfacing with lmt. This R package is developed via R6 package which can provides an implementation of encapsulated object-oriented programming for R. And this makes the grammar of Rlmt looks like easy and elegant (i hope 😄).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blupADC</title>
      <link>/project/blupadc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/blupadc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blupADC&lt;/code&gt; is an useful and powerful tool for handling genomic data and pedigree data in animal and plant breeding(&lt;strong&gt;traditional blup and genomic selection&lt;/strong&gt;). In the design of this package, most of data analysis problems in breeding have been considered, and the speed of calculation is also the key point. In terms of the speed, the core functions of this package are coded by c++ (&lt;code&gt;Rcpp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;RcppArmadillo &lt;/code&gt;) , and it also supports parallel calculation (by applying &lt;code&gt;openMP&lt;/code&gt; programming) and big data calculation(by importing &lt;code&gt;bigmemory &lt;/code&gt; package).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blupADC&lt;/code&gt; provides many useful functions for the whole steps for animal and plant breeding, including pedigree analysis(&lt;strong&gt;trace pedigree, rename pedigree, and correct pedigree errors&lt;/strong&gt;), genotype data format conversion(supports &lt;strong&gt;Hapmap, Plink, Blupf90, Numeric, VCF and Haplotype&lt;/strong&gt; format), genotype data quality control and imputation, construction of kinship matrix(&lt;strong&gt;pedigree, genomic and single-step&lt;/strong&gt;),and genetic evaluation( by interfacing with two famous breeding softwares, &lt;strong&gt;DMU&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;BLUPF90&lt;/strong&gt; in an easy way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we kindly provides an easier way of applying &lt;code&gt;blupADC&lt;/code&gt;, which is a free website(&lt;a href=&#34;http://47.95.251.15:443/blupADC/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shinyapp&lt;/a&gt;). Several functions are still under development. But the pitfall of this website is that it can&amp;rsquo;t handle big data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cBar2</title>
      <link>/project/cbar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cbar2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cBar2&lt;/code&gt; is an useful and powerful tool for handling two-way cross breeding in animal and plant breeding. In addition, it provides a powerful function to do allele tracing for this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By applying this package, user can complete the genetic evaluation with three different types of partial relationship matrix(pedigree, genomic, and single-step partial relationship matrix).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
